<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-10T22:22:34-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//</id><title type="html">Mathew Rupp</title><subtitle>Keeping It Real Since 1988.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">An Idea Appears</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/27/An-Idea-Appears.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Idea Appears" /><published>2018-10-27T10:17:01-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T10:17:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/27/An%20Idea%20Appears</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/27/An-Idea-Appears.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay…So…I Have an idea…A project If you will….something to motivate me and a clear path to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create Trello Board For Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish refreshing Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a Visual Mockup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mongo Refresh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OATH…Github Integration Initially?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profit…not…you know actually profit…but…emotionally?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;#winning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay…so how to I cram this into my busy schedule?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M-F Wake up at 5:30…this means bedtime is….10pm. My goal is to have this prototype completed by New Years Day. 66 days….totally doable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Saturday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goal Setting</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/22/Goal-Setting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goal Setting" /><published>2018-10-22T10:17:01-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T10:17:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/22/Goal-Setting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/10/22/Goal-Setting.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Today we’re talking about goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals can be awesome. Goals can be frightening. But goals can mostly be effective. Recently I learned about a program called “Beeminder”. The Premise is simple. You put in a goal, commit a dollar amount to it, and then try and stay on track or it  &lt;strong&gt;costs you money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how well this will work, but I look forward to giving it a try. Beeminder has a few decent integrations that I want utilize in order to set my goals. But first I need some goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice my programming regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lose Weight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete more workshop projects/products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####So now that we have a list of things to do what comes next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to tackle our goals is to break them down into bitesized chunks. By splitting them up it makes them achievable. So now lets look at each of the 3 categories and break them out into smaller goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Programming Practice
There are lots of metrics I could use to gauge my programming practice. I could track files created, time spent programming, videos watched or articles read or any other random method of tracking. However, Beeminder has github integration, so I have decided to track total commits per week to my github. This will force me to regularly make commits to projects I am working on. That includes these posts. I have it set as 7 commits per week, but we will see if that needs to be adjusted to a greater amount based on commits. If I’m doing multiple commits a day, then it really doesn’t give me any incentive throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Weight Loss
For right now, I’m just going to track calories eaten. This will get me back in the habit of logging what I eat, which tends to force me to eat better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Completing More Workshop Projects
This will probably be the most difficult habit to get into. Between school, life, and everything else. Finding time to just relax in the workshop and build things has been extremely limited. I would like to be able to create a minimum of 3 products per week, so I have set that up as a goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the goals I am setting for myself to run through the rest of the year. With only two months left in 2018, I feel setting these up will give me a great start on 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Monday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DO something WHILE I Search My Memory FOR This Information</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/14/Do-something.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DO something WHILE I Search My Memory FOR This Information" /><published>2018-09-14T10:17:01-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-14T10:17:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/14/Do%20something</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/14/Do-something.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay…soooo here’s today’s progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refamiliarization with arrays and objects, as well as loops. Now…Loops are where I have struggled in the past…and it’s still a bit of a point of friction in the flow and getting the browser to display what I want…but I’m figuring it out. So here is what I’m doing to get to where I need to be employable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: The Odin Project…basically a self paced reference based course.
Step 2: Mix in the parts of The Complete Webdeveloper Bootcamp course I have on Udemy.
Step 3: Mix in some youtube and other references I find.
Step 4: Profit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend has us running a ton of errands but I will try to work on this at least an hour a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also going to be working on the mockup for the Porche 911 site I have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Friday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Annnnd We’re Back</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/13/Annnnnd-We-Are-Back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Annnnd We're Back" /><published>2018-09-13T20:17:01-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-13T20:17:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/13/Annnnnd-We-Are-Back</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2018/09/13/Annnnnd-We-Are-Back.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…I stopped studying for a while. Bouncing mental images had me jumping from language to language. Well…I’m unemployed right now…so I need to make money. I am working on catching back up to where I was before I jumped off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken up following the Odin Project, so I will combine that with the courses I have on udemy…those will be the only two main sources for right now. Once I finish those I will try to apply for a local job as either a full-stack web developer or a front-end developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will probably be making a few sites as a demonstration of my skills along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas I have for a projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A website that details the evolution of the Porche 911&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An E-Commerce Store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A social based experience for motorcycle trips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway…will continue to work on these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thursday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I-AM-THE-POSTMAN</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/06/I-AM-THE-POSTMAN!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-AM-THE-POSTMAN" /><published>2017-11-06T18:15:01-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T18:15:01-08:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/06/I-AM-THE-POSTMAN!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/06/I-AM-THE-POSTMAN!.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well..this weekend was long and full of terrors…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fact-the-days-of-24-hour-video-game-playing-has-passed-no-longer-am-i-able-to-withstand-the-clocks-torment-as-the-seconds-turn-to-minutes-and-the-minutes-turn-to-hours&quot;&gt;Fact: The days of 24 hour video game playing has passed. No longer am I able to withstand the clock’s torment as the seconds turn to minutes, and the minutes turn to hours.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend Katy hosted a 24 hour video game livestream for the ExtraLife organization. The goal was to raise money for childrens hospitals…and that involved us playing video games for 24 hours. I was not required to participate…but I did so anyway…well..for 22.5 of them…I ended up taking an hour and a half nap….totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway…with the livestream requiring a hefty amount of setup, I was not able to study friday-sunday….so I accomplished nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I could barely suffer through a few lessons…but did learn about post requests. I was able to code along and make a page that updates with information from a text box….dont know if I could do it from memory…but I could figure it out I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow…we go deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Monday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ALL-THE-THINGS</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/02/ALL-THE-THINGS!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ALL-THE-THINGS" /><published>2017-11-02T17:55:01-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-02T17:55:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/02/ALL-THE-THINGS!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/11/02/ALL-THE-THINGS!.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;THURSDAY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOLY LIGHTSPEED BATMAN!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been a blitz on the coursework…I know I havn’t updated this much…but I have been super deep in the learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When last we left off I had just coded a front end “app” that was a basic todo list…which was awesome…but the todo’s were not persistant…well since then…guess what!?!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking that now they might be persistant? If so than you are….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrong&quot;&gt;Wrong!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah…I haven’t touched the todo list app since I published the last post…but here is what I have done…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set up a cloud9 IDE…I intend to install Node on a Raspberry pi at somepoint…but until then…cloud9 handles that hassle which lets me focus on the learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday…halloween…got a little done. Learned about Node.js and how it works on the serverside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set up a Node environment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Got some more practice using command line commands…I knew most of the ones the course covered…but it is good to get a refresher and some practice using them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learned about the express framework…and about NPM…and installing Node packages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learned about Get requests…and routes…and how to serve info to routes….and how to use variables in them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learned about EJS…or embedded javascript…and how to use EJS to serve a variable to a template page…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this has been fairly abstract…and while I feel I could fumble around with this and get a header to display a page name based on an imput in the URL field, I have a feeling it will really start to come together in the next few days so I can generate pages dynamically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is really rambly..but oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">THURSDAY</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New To-Do</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/30/New-Todo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New To-Do" /><published>2017-10-30T14:35:01-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-30T14:35:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/30/New-Todo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/30/New-Todo.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little slow going this past week. Life has been keeping me very active…also I’ve been feeling slightly lazy….so there is that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANYWAY. Finished my first todo app today. Went through the course walkthrough step by step this time instead of jumping ahead…made it so I could actually get through without feeling drained or frustrated because I did something that works…but is not where the course is going. It’s not a great todo app…it doesn’t save tasks…so no persistance…but as far as front end stuff goes it was a good tutorial. I feel like I could make it by myself if I did it again…might do that…we’ll see. I really like the simplicity that jQuery adds to Javascript…makes it much quicker to work stuff out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway..if you want to check out the todo progress, it’s listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cybnew.github.io/Todo-app/&quot; title=&quot;Todo App&quot;&gt;Todo App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Monday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello jQuery</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/26/Hello-jQuery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello jQuery" /><published>2017-10-26T21:45:01-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-26T21:45:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/26/Hello-jQuery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/26/Hello-jQuery.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ohhello-there&quot;&gt;Oh…hello there…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been working with jQuery this week…and I like it. It makes things much faster!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently “you don’t need jQuery” according to some people…and I will agree…in some situations you shouldn’t use jQuery…I mean…you can accomplish anything you want with Vanilla JS..but I can also walk to work every day, yet I drive…because it makes me WAY faster. For example….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;var buttons = document.querySelectorAll(&quot;button&quot;);

for (var i = 0; i &amp;lt; buttons.length; i++){
	buttons[i].addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, function(){
		this.style.backgroundColor(&quot;purple&quot;)
	}
	)};
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can be written as…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$(&quot;button&quot;).on(&quot;click&quot;, function(){
	this.css(&quot;background&quot;,&quot;purple&quot;)
	})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much easier right???!?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway…tomorrow I start my first todo project…built with HTML, CSS, and JS/jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thursday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Have Completion</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/22/We-have-completion..html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Have Completion" /><published>2017-10-22T21:45:01-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-22T21:45:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/22/We-have-completion.</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/22/We-have-completion..html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plague-has-passed&quot;&gt;The plague has passed.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took all damn week but I am finally over the stupid cold I had. Being sick really took it out of me this week, so I pretty much avoided anything programming related beyond a youtube video or two.. But…since I am FINALLY feeling better, I figured I would dig deep into the rest of the basic javascript section. What does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…I finally finished the RGB color guessing game from the Udemy Course. It usually takes me about 35 minutes to complete a 15 minute video. Usually it’s because I pause it right before the instructor explains it, and I try to figure it out for myself. I have mixed feelings on the benifits of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. It gets me thinking about how to solve the problem…which is good. I have gotten in the habit of separating my code out (I guess it counts as refactoring) before the instructor finishes explaining a way to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But it gets me pointed down a path (branch?) that diverts from the course, which is fine…but if the course takes a slightly different direction, it takes me for forever to redirect my code towards the solution. Urg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight things went pretty damn well up until the final refactoring. I spent 21 minutes searching for what happened to be a comma that escapted the file…I could have sworn it was there when I started. Unfortunately, while I was searching for what turned out to be a missing comma, Katy was busy searching through her sewing patterns…we learned that I don’t focus well with crinkling craft paper in the background. &lt;strong&gt;looks at Katy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. RGB game is finished. If you want to check it out you can click the link below.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cybnew.github.io/rgbgame/&quot; title=&quot;RGB Guessing Game&quot;&gt;RGB Guessing Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I start with jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will post more soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sunday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Standby</title><link href="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/18/Standby.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Standby" /><published>2017-10-18T20:17:01-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-18T20:17:01-07:00</updated><id>https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/18/Standby</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cybnew.github.io/mrupp-blog//progress/2017/10/18/Standby.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slightly dead. Consumed by cold meds. Havn’t coded since monday. Head is foggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus side…playing around with illustrator…doodling..pretty fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might post some doodles soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought of project I want to do, simple color scheme generator…with vector graphics being affected by color choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is rambling….I know…how about a haiku?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head cold has me sacked-
Sudafed has me loopy-
Time to not be sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Mat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Wednesday</summary></entry></feed>